<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Camel Dashboard Operator</title><link>/</link><description>Recent content on Camel Dashboard Operator</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Hawt.io Openshift Console Plugin</title><link>/docs/plugins/hawtio/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/plugins/hawtio/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Import a Camel application</title><link>/docs/configuration/import/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/configuration/import/</guid><description>&lt;p>The operator is instructed to watch &lt;code>Deployment&lt;/code> and verify if they are marked as Camel application. You will likely need to update your deployment process and include automatically a &lt;code>camel.apache.org/app&lt;/code> label for all the applications you want to monitor.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>NOTE: you can configure the operator to watch for a different label setting the environment variable &lt;code>LABEL_SELECTOR&lt;/code> in the operator Pod.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="collect-camel-metrics">Collect Camel metrics&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The operator is designed to consume the services exposed by &lt;a href="https://camel.apache.org/components/next/others/observability-services.html">Camel Observability Services component&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Camel Openshift Console Plugin</title><link>/docs/plugins/oc-console/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/plugins/oc-console/</guid><description>&lt;p>This operator can work standalone and you can use the data exposed in the &lt;code>CamelApp&lt;/code> custom resource accordingly. However it has a great fit with the &lt;a href="https://github.com/camel-tooling/camel-openshift-console-plugin?tab=readme-ov-file#deployment-to-openshift">Camel Openshift Console Plugin&lt;/a>, which is a visual representation of the services exposed by the operator.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="camel-openshift-console-plugin-dependencies-matrix">Camel Openshift Console Plugin dependencies matrix&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The Camel Openshift Console Plugin is an extension of OpenShift Console exposing the data from the Camel Dashboard Operator.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Below you can find the compatibility list for its dependencies:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Configure Camel application</title><link>/docs/configuration/tuning/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/configuration/tuning/</guid><description>&lt;p>There are several configuration you can apply separately to each of your Camel application. They mostly work at general level (setting an environment variable on the operator) or at application level (setting an annotation on the Deployment resource).&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="configure-the-metrics-polling">Configure the metrics polling&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>You can watch the metrics evolving as long as the application is running, for example via &lt;code>-w&lt;/code> parameter:&lt;/p>
&lt;pre tabindex="0">&lt;code>kubectl get camelapps -w

NAME PHASE LAST EXCHANGE EXCHANGE SLI IMAGE REPLICAS INFO
...
camel-app-413 Running 8m32s OK squakez/cdb:4.13 1 Main - 4.13.0-SNAPSHOT (4.13.0-SNAPSHOT)
camel-app-main Running OK docker.io/squakez/db-app-main:1.0 1 Main - 4.11.0 (4.11.0)
camel-app-quarkus Running Warning docker.io/squakez/db-app-quarkus:1.0 1
camel-app-sb Running Error docker.io/squakez/db-app-sb:1.0 1 Spring-Boot - 3.4.3 (4.11.0)
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;p>The &lt;code>CamelApp&lt;/code> are polled every minute by default. It should be enough in most cases, as the project is really a dashboard and not a proper monitoring tool. However, you can change this configuration if you want a more or less reactive polling. You can configure this value both at operator level (which would affect all the applications) or at single application level.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>